<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<brand xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
   <links>
	  <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=UTF-8"/>
      <link rel="stylesheet" href="css/default/results.css" type="text/css"/>
	  <link rel="shortcut icon" href="icons/default/favicon.ico" />
   </links>
   
 	<googleanalytics>
		<script>
			(function(i,s,o,g,r,a,m){i['GoogleAnalyticsObject']=r;i[r]=i[r]||function(){(i[r].q=i[r].q||[]).push(arguments)},i[r].l=1*new Date();a=s.createElement(o), m=s.getElementsByTagName(o)[0];a.async=1;a.src=g;m.parentNode.insertBefore(a,m)})(window,document,'script','//www.google-analytics.com/analytics.js','ga');
			ga('create', 'UA-55198916-1', 'auto', {'allowLinker': true});
			ga('require', 'linker');
			ga('linker:autoLink', ['ucop.edu', 'uci.edu', 'berkeley.edu', 'ucla.edu']);
			ga('send', 'pageview');
		</script>
	</googleanalytics>  
	<header>
		<div id="logout">
			<p>
				<img alt="Dash: Open data for the global research community" src="assets/img/dash_ucmerced_logo.png" title="Dash: Open data for the global research community" />
			</p>
		</div>
		<br class="clear" />
	</header> 
	
	<homelink>
		<a href="/xtf/search">UC Merced Dash</a>
	</homelink>

   <footer>
		<div id="footer-logos">
			<div id="cdl-logo-sm"><a href="http://www.cdlib.org/"><img src="assets/img/cdl-logo.jpg" width="72" height="26" alt="California Digital Library" title="California Digital Library" /></a></div>
			<div id="cdl-logo-text">Dash is a service of the <a href="http://www.cdlib.org/services/uc3/">University of California Curation Center of the California Digital Library</a>. <br />Copyright &#169; 2014 The Regents of the University of California</div>
			<div id="local-lib-sm"><a href="http://cdlib.org/uc3/"><img src="assets/img/uc3.png" width="72" alt="UC Curation Center" title="UC Curation Center"/></a></div>
			<div id="local-lib-text">Dash is a collaborative project between the <br /><a href="http://library.ucmerced.edu">UC Merced Library</a> and the <a href="http://cdlib.org/uc3">UC Curation Center</a>.</div>
		</div> 
	</footer>

	<faq>
		<div class="text-container">
			<h2 class="title">Who can deposit data here?</h2>
			<p class="para">Any UC Merced-affiliated researcher (faculty, postdoc, student, or staff) can use this resource to archive and share research datasets, provided they have appropriate permission. Data that are collected at research sites are under the stewardship of the Principal Investigator (PI) named on the resource provided to collect the data, and this PI may grant permission to deposit data.</p>

			<h2 class="title">What if I have collaborators outside of UC Merced?</h2>
			<p class="para">You will need UC Merced credentials to log into the system and deposit data. You can, however, add your collaborators to the "data contributors" section of the metadata. Although only researchers logged in with UC Merced credentials can deposit data, anyone can search, view and download datasets in Dash.</p>

			<h2 class="title">Who can access these datasets?</h2>
			<p class="para">All data in Dash have <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution</a> (CC-BY-4.0) licenses. This means anyone can access the datasets, download them, and use them provided they give proper attribution. Although many researchers would prefer to maintain more control over who downloads and uses their data, we believe that having data that are fully open is the best way to enable academic advancement. Read <a href="http://pantonprinciples.org">Panton Principles for Open Data in Science</a> for more information.</p>

			<h2 class="title">Do you support data embargoes or restricted access?</h2>
			<p class="para">Not at this time. We do, however, have plans to expand the Dash functionality to include both. If you have specific requests for functionality, please add it to our <a href="https://github.com/CDLUC3/dash/issues">GitHub Issue Tracker</a>.</p>

			<h2 class="title">What do I need to submit the data?</h2>
			<ul>
				<li>Permission from the appropriate PI(s)</li>
				<li>Information about the dataset, including dataset title, creators, keywords</li>
				<li>Access to files comprising the dataset</li>
			</ul>

			<h2 class="title">Are there any file format requirements?</h2>
			<p class="para">No. Files of any type are acceptable for deposit. Ideally, file types will be non-proprietary. If you have files of a specialized or proprietary nature, be sure they are accompanied by any pertinent information that would allow the proper viewing and/or usage of the file. This information could be stored in a separate 'Readme' document within the dataset files, or could be entered in the 'Technical Description' section of the metadata.</p>

			<h2 class="title">What best practices can I follow for data preparation?</h2>
			<p class="para">There are a variety of best practices depending on your field of research. For generic help, see the <a href="http://www.dataone.org/sites/all/documents/DataONE_BP_Primer_020212.pdf">DataONE Primer on Data Management Best Practices</a> (PDF). Generally,</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Ensure data files are the most up-to-date and complete versions</li>
				<li>Ensure the integrity of data files (check if corrupted)</li>
				<li>Ensure that all data relating to human subjects has been properly de-identified</li>
				<li>Double-check the accuracy of the descriptive metadata</li>
				<li>Enter as much descriptive metadata as possible in the indexing fields</li>
				<li>Ensure that any information critical to the proper viewing and/or usage of the data is included in the submission (either as a separate 'Readme' file or within the 'Technical Description' metadata field)</li>
			</ul>

			<h2 class="title">For how long will the data be available?</h2>
			<p class="para">Once you have deposited data, it is permanently archived and available through the <a href="http://cdlib.org">California Digital Library</a>'s <a href="https://merritt.cdlib.org">Merritt Repository Service</a>. See our <a href="/xtf/search?smode=policiesPage">Policies page</a> for more information.</p>

			<h2 class="title">Can I update my data?</h2>
			<p class="para">Yes, you can add new versions of your data.</p>

			<h2 class="title">How will someone find my data?</h2>
			<p class="para">Metadata will be indexed by the <a href="http://wokinfo.com/products_tools/multidisciplinary/dci/about/">Thomson-Reuters Data Citation Index</a> and <a href="http://wokinfo.com/products_tools/multidisciplinary/dci/about/">Scopus</a>.</p>

			<h2 class="title">Do the data have to be associated with a publication?</h2>
			<p class="para">No. Dash accepts all quality data, regardless of whether they have been used to publish a paper.</p>

			<h2 class="title">Do I need to log into Dash to get data?</h2>
			<p class="para">Anyone can search, view and download datasets in Dash. Persons requesting data are not required to sign-in in order to do so.</p>

			<h2 class="title">Do I have to pay for data?</h2>
			<p class="para">No, these data are made publicly available free of charge.</p>

			<h2 class="title">What if I have questions about the data?</h2>
			<p class="para">Please contact us at <a href="mailto:curation@ucmerced.edu">curation@ucmerced.edu</a> with any questions about the data. Your message will be directed to an appropriate source to answer any questions about Dash and data curation.</p>
		</div>
	</faq>

	<about>
		<h2>What is Dash?</h2>
		<p>Dash is designed to be a simple, self-service solution for researchers to archive and share their datasets.</p>
		<p>Using Dash, you can:</p>
		<ul>
			<li>Prepare data for sharing by reviewing best practice guidance for the creation or acquisition of digital research data.</li>
			<li>Select data for sharing through local file browse or drag-and-drop operation.</li>
			<li>Describe data in terms of the <a href="http://datacite.org">DataCite</a> metadata schema.</li>
			<li>Identify data with a persistent DOI for permanent citation and discovery.</li>
			<li>Preserve, manage, and share data.</li>
			<li>Discover and retrieve data through faceted search and browse.</li>
		</ul>
		<h2>Why Share Data?</h2>
		<p>Sharing your data</p>
		<ul>
			<li>fosters increased collaborations among researchers;</li>
			<li>facilitates validation and recognition of your work;</li>
			<li>allows institutions and funders to gauge the impact of their resources; and</li>
			<li>advances the pace at which research, and knowledge, can progress around the globe.</li>
		</ul>
		<h2>Who Provides this Service?</h2>
		<p>UC Merced Library is partnering with the Resource Center for Community Engaged Scholarship (<a href="http://communityresearch.ucmerced.edu/">ReCCES</a>) to promote and assure public access to research conducted at UC Merced that impacts our communities.</p>
		<p>UC Merced Dash is a collaborative project between the UC Merced Library and the UC Curation Center (UC3) at the California Digital Library.</p>
	</about>

</brand>
